{
    "id": "865cb53533154596a1bfd676a487b43b",
    "title": "Coordinating conjunctions worksheet",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "af75004b789e48029f8b9aa73201a484",
            "title": "Coordinating Conjunctions Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "They were poor, ………………. often suffered great hardship.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "and",
                        "but"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He overslept himself …………………. thus missed the train.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "and",
                        "but"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "That coat cannot be mine, ……………… it is too big for me.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "and",
                        "but",
                        "for"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "As a boy he had never been to school, and ………………….. he had no opportunity of learning to read and write.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "therefore",
                        "for",
                        "yet"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "This must not happen again, ……………… you will be dismissed.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "or",
                        "but",
                        "and"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is rich, ………………. he is not happy.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "and",
                        "therefore",
                        "but"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Hurry up, ……………….. you will be late.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "and",
                        "or",
                        "yet"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He must have done his duty, ……………….. he is a conscientious man.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "so",
                        "therefore"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He tried hard, ………………. he did not succeed.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "but",
                        "and",
                        "so"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The parents were horrified ………………. they saw blood stains on the floor and no sign of their child.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "therefore",
                        "for",
                        "so"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}